# Dr. Po-Hsun Tseng

6+ years experience of large-scale software development with C programming on the Linux system throughout my Ph.D. journey. Seeking a challenging and rewarding opportunity with low-level system programming (eg. device driver, Linux kernel, CPU architecture) to apply my skills at a fabless company.



## CONTACT

zengbs@gmail.com

+886 966 587 832

Hsinchu, Taiwan

https://github.com/zengbs

# **SKILLS**

#### **Programming**

C
Bash scripting
System programming
CUDA
Python



### **Operating System**

Linux - user Linux - kernel



#### Architecture

**ARM** architecture



#### Software & Tools

Git Vim Gdb Valgrind



#### Languages

Chinese (native)
English - writing
English - speaking
English - listening
English - reading



## **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. in Computational Physics

**♀** National Taiwan University, Taiwan

**1** 08/2016 - 06/2022

 $\bullet$  Developed and implemented a new algorithm to reduce numerical error by  $10^6$  compared to conventional one.

See Fig. 16 in (https://arxiv.org/abs/2012.11130).

- Designed a new approach to further promote the robustness of GAMER. The new approach was adopted in the research project led by Dr. Kuo-Chuan Pan from Tsing Hua University. (https://github.com/gamer-project/gamer/pull/60)
- Worked on improving the GAMER collaborated with Dr. Tzihong Chiueh and Dr. Hsi-Yu Schive. See the Section References.
- A main contributor of the GAMER.
   (https://github.com/gamer-project/gamer/graphs/contributors)
- Built NIS, NFS, and Linux cluster from scratch with colleagues and worked with Dr. Hsi-Yu Schive to bootstrap simulations for research.

# **WORK HISTORY**

Circuit designer

**♀** TDK corporation, Singapore

**1** 01/2015 - 02/2016

• Designed the circiut of surface acoustic wave(SAW) filters

Military service

**6** 08/2013 - 08/2014

# **EDUCATION**

M.Sc. in Physics

**♀** National Taiwan University, Taiwan

**1** 09/2011 - 07/2013

B.Sc. in Mathematics

**1** 09/2006 - 07/2011

# **SOFT SKILLS**

Nonverbal communication Active listening Open mindedness

Patience Mutual respect Teamwork Brainstorming

Collaboration

# **GENERAL SKILLS**

Numerical algorithm Large-scale project cscope makefile

**GNU** autotools

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- [1] An adaptive mesh, GPU-accelerated, and error minimized special relativistic hydrodynamics code
- Po-Hsun Tseng, Hsi-Yu Schive, Tzihong Chiueh
- Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society 2021 Vol. 504, pp. 3298-3315

https://arxiv.org/abs/2012.11130

- [2] The symmetry problem of the Fermi and eROSITA bubbles: A proof-of-concept study
- Po-Hsun Tseng, Hsiang-Yi Karen Yang, Hsi-Yu Schive, Chun-Yen Chen, Tzihong Chiueh
- preprint 2022

## **TALKS**

- An adaptive-mesh, GPU-accelerated, and optimally error-controlled special relativistic hydrodynamics code
   Oral (remote), American Center for Physics College Park, U.S.A
   Mar. 2021
- A new and accurate code for simulating special relativistic hydrodynamics Oral, Annual Meeting of the Physical Society of Taiwan, NPTU.

Feb. 2020

## **REFERENCES**

- Please send an appointment letter to request a call. 😃
- Dr. Tzihong Chiueh

Distinguished Professor, Institute of Astrophysics, National Taiwan University

- ▼ Taipei 10617, Taiwan
- chiuehth@phys.ntu.edu.tw
- **4886 2 3366 8628**
- Dr. Hsi-Yu Schive

Assistant Professor, Institute of Astrophysics, National Taiwan University

- ▼ Taipei 10617, Taiwan
- hyschive@phys.ntu.edu.tw
- **\** +886 2 3366 8644
- Dr. Hsiang-Yi Karen Yang

Assistant Professor, Institute of Astronomy, National Tsing Hua University

- ♥ Hsinchu 30013, Taiwan
- hyang@phys.nthu.edu.tw
- **4886 3 574 2953**